# **Amel Khiri**

## **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

kh.amelle@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

As a Full Stack Software Developer, I have a passion for creating engaging and accessible applications. With experience in front-end and back-end development, I specialize in using JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, and SQL. As a remote pair-programming expert, I have mentored over 20 students and completed 300+code reviews. I have strong communication and problem-solving skills, combined with a solid work ethic and attention to detail. I hold a Master's Degree in Material Science and possess a Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering.

#### **SKILLS**

- Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Jest.
- Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Postgresql, Devise, SQL Cancancan, REST-API.
- Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Webpack, mobile/responsive development, Jira, RSpec, TDD, OOP, Jest, Capybara, JSON, Kanban, Agile, NodeJs, unit testing, debugging.
- **Professional**: Remote pair-programming, teamwork, mentoring, constant learning, communication, critical thinking, problem solving, organization skills, time management, work ethic, attention to detail.
- Languages: Arabic, French, English, Turkish, Notions of Spanish.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **MICROVERSE**

Technical Support Engineer May, 2022 - Present

Remote

- Completed over 300 code reviews in Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS for over 60 students.
- Mentored 20+ students on a 1:1 basis, providing technical and professional assistance as they complete individual and group projects in JavaScript, React, and Ruby on Rails.
- Provided feedback and assisted students in adding features to their projects.

#### **JUSTICE 4.0**

Remote

#### **Full Stack Developer**

May 2022 - July 2022

• Conducted front-end, back-end, and database web development for a web application that connects the public with court services in Finland.

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

September 2021 - Present

- Mentored junior 20+ web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program, resulting in a 5% increase in program retention.

#### AHMED AROUA TECHNOLOGUY INSTITUTE

M'sila, Algeria

**Mechanical Design Professor** 

September 2003 - June 2022

- Over 10 years of experience teaching mechanical design to students of all ages.
- Proven track record of helping students develop a strong understanding of mechanical design principles.

• Fostered positive relationships with students, parents, and colleagues, resulting in a 95% satisfaction rating in end-of-year evaluations

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **MICROVERSE**

#### **September 2021 - July 2022**

#### Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Completed over 1300 hours of training in algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development, while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard Gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

## M B. UNIVERSITY ALGERIA Algeria Masters Degree, Material Science

**September 2018 - July 2019** 

- Successfully earned a Master of Science in Material Science with a specialization in advanced materials engineering
- Developed a comprehensive understanding of the properties and characteristics of various materials
- Gained expertise in the design and fabrication of materials for a variety of applications
- Conducted research on the development of new materials and their potential applications
- Utilized advanced analytical techniques to evaluate the performance of materials
- Applied knowledge of material science to solve complex engineering problems

# IOMP, UFAS Algeria

**September 1993 - June 1998** 

# Mechanical Engineer,

- Possess a Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering from a top-tier university, with a focus on design, analysis, and fabrication of mechanical systems.
- 3+ years experience using CAD software, including Solid Works, AutoCAD, to design and analyze mechanical components and systems.
- Skilled in the use of FEA software, to simulate and analyze the performance of mechanical systems.
- Proficient in the use of MATLAB to develop and analyze data from experiments.
- Knowledgeable in the use of machining tools and processes to fabricate mechanical components.
- Experienced in the use of materials science principles to select and analyze materials for mechanical components.

#### HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building 20+ full-stack projects both independently and via pair-programming. Some of them are listed below:

#### WishYacht:

Web application that allows users to rent and reserve yachts. Live demo

- Built with: React, Redux, CSS, Bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails, Devise Jwt, Postgresql, and Rspec.

#### **Space Traveler's Hub:**

Web application to track and reserve missions and rockets.

- Built with: React, Redux, and API. | <u>Live demo</u>

# YourWallet:

Mobile web application to manage budget.

- Built with: Ruby on Rails. Live demo